<WiBitNet><Courses count="7"><Course><CurriculumID>1</CurriculumID><CourseID>1</CourseID><Title>Introduction to Computer Programming</Title><Nickname>Intro</Nickname><Description>This is our fundamentals course! Software development is not all glamorous. There are many underlying concepts that lay beneath the code that are important to understand in order to reach your full potential. The WiBit.Net training method focuses on basics. Why? Well, for a simple reason. If we work from the foundation and build upwards then there is no need to reiterate information with each new lesson. When we start talking about decision statements and loop structures in actual programming languages you are already aware of what they are and how they operate! As time progresses the learning speed increases and you will walk out with a strong understanding of what is going on!

All this learning begins here with Introduction to Computer Programming. We will begin this course with a casual conversation of what Kevin and Bryan have gained through their over a decade as developers. As the lessons progress, you will be exposed to other exciting topics such as common languages, core concepts, flow charts, pseudo code, variables, data types, formulas, basic binary, APIs, IPCs and bitwise operations (not necessarily in that order).</Description></Course><Course><CurriculumID>1</CurriculumID><CourseID>2</CourseID><Title>Programming in C</Title><Nickname>C</Nickname><Description>Although ancient, C is the Mother of programming languages. It is not common for software developers to have a background in C now-a-days, however, the languages that dominate the landscape today have their roots in the C Language (Java, C#, Objective-C, C++, Perl, the list goes on). By starting your programming knowledge with the C Language you instantly place yourself in the best position possible to more effectively translate your skills into other languages.

We will be taking you on a great adventure with Kevin and Bryan as we go from ground to ceiling through the C language. When you start, you will be equiped with only a text editor and walk out knowing how to build wicked fast dlls that can be consumed in other higher level languages.

This language is also considered to be our 'foundation' language as almost everything else we teach here will be based on the original concepts and approach to learning C. Now go get started!</Description></Course><Course><CurriculumID>1</CurriculumID><CourseID>3</CourseID><Title>Introduction To Object Oriented Programming</Title><Nickname>Intro OOP</Nickname><Description>Ok! We have a solid understanding of the basics of programming and we are proficient in C. What is the next step? Well, it's C++! But wait... Hold on! Before we make that leap, let's put our learning hats back on and learn the fundamentals of Object Oriented Programming (OOP). The only REAL difference between C and C++ is OOP. Before we even start looking at this concept let's learn the fundamentals!

We have found over the years that many developers struggle with OOP. It makes sense! It's a weird wacky concept. If you start programming in C# or Java you have no true exposure to the bottom level. By starting in the OOP world you are doing yourself a disservice. It is only when you start at the bottom that you truly understand where you've been and where you're going.

Have you ever worked a job and knew a manager that didn't rise up the ranks? Perhaps they were put in their position because they knew a guy that knew a guy? Well, this is like a programmer that starts learning in OOP. They miss out on a lot and lack the basic fundamentals. This person is doomed to struggle or fail.

The manager that started from the bottom and rose to the top knows how business functions at the grassroots and has a better knowledgebase to make more sound decisions. This is you! Starting in C and moving your way up will, in the end, make you a much better programmer.... We promise!

Sit back, relax, and enjoy a fun colorful ride through the many unique aspects of OOP. We will talk about what OOP is, what characteristics it possesses, how this concept is used conceptually, and much more!</Description></Course><Course><CurriculumID>1</CurriculumID><CourseID>4</CourseID><Title>Programming in C++</Title><Nickname>C++</Nickname><Description>The time has come. Your destiny is taking shape. You are taking your next big leap in your journey of becoming the greatest software developer the world has ever seen! Well maybe... Don't hold us liable for that or anything... C++ is the most important programming language to learn. If you have gotten this far you probably already know a lot about C++, or at least have heard some things. We are stepping up from our procedural language predecessor (C) and jumping into the world of Object Oriented Programming. You can probably begin to see how our learning structure is baby stepping you into the high level languages. You have learned the basics of what programming is, then C and now C++! Pretty sweet transition, if we do say so ourselves!

We know that C++ has its roots in the 1970's, which those of us keeping time know that this was a long time ago. How can something from the 70's have any relevance today? I mean, disco is dead! No one has a harry chest with the first three buttons undone and a gold chain (we hope anyway)! Last I checked Tom Selleck, Burt Reynolds and Susan Summers aren't sex symbols anymore. How is it possible that C++ has stood the test of time? Well... for one very simple reason... IT'S AWESOME!

Many modern languages today were inspired by C++. It is imperative to learn C++ before even attempting Java or C# or any other OOP language. Syntax structure for C++ is pretty much the same as C and other higher level languages follow similar syntax and program structure as C++.

In this course you will pick up where C left off! We will begin with the major differences between C and C++ and then very quickly get into classes. The first classes we will use are not ones that we create, but rather classes that our friends from the 70's wrote for us! Then we will write our own super awesome classes! We will then move right into advanced programming techniques such as multithreading, delegation, properties, and even basic GUI development.</Description></Course><Course><CurriculumID>1</CurriculumID><CourseID>5</CourseID><Title>Programming in Objective-C</Title><Nickname>Objective-C</Nickname><Description>The year was 1986. Sammy Hagar joined Van Halen... Matlock started its 10 year run on TV... Top Gun was Top Dog at the box office... Ferris Bueller took his infamous day off... Nintendo released The Legend of Zelda on NES... AND a little known programming called Objective-C trots its way out on the scene. This course will focus on the other popular &quot;bolt-on&quot; object oriented programming language: Objective-C. Just like C++, this language is attached to C. Even though this and C++ have a similar philosophy they are both extremely different languages. We will be focusing on the Apple implementation of the language and use aspects of the Cocoa Framework. As we progress through this language you will be excelled through a series of basic labs compiling on the command terminal and very quickly thrown in to Xcode (the premiere IDE for the Apple platform). You will even learn how to write Mac OS X and iPhone applications! Not bad for a beginner course, right?

You will not only be exposed to these awesome exercises, but you will know what you are doing at the end of it! No BS material that teases you by showing you just how to make a button. We will open the hood of Objective-C and see what makes her go! Be prepared for a wild ride!</Description></Course><Course><CurriculumID>1</CurriculumID><CourseID>6</CourseID><Title>Programming in Java</Title><Nickname>Java</Nickname><Description>A long time ago, in a decade far far away called... the nineties, there was a birth. As word of this birth spread throughout the world many rejoiced as others worried. Were we witnessing the birth of a savior, or the birth of a Demon? As developers around the globe learned of this new prodigy, they all began to blindly follow their newly appointed leader. With promises as the &quot;next big thing&quot; and with the guidance of the testament of Time Magazines Best Products of 1995 as there creed, Sun Microsystems began spreading the word of Java throughout the land. IT managers as far as the eye could see were becoming enriched by the spoils of Java. And then... it happened... Technical support centers were barraged with angry customers asking such questions as &quot;Why is this running so slow?&quot;, &quot;Why do I get a 'Java out of memory' error when I try to copy 3 lines of text?&quot;, and &quot;Are Java applets supposed to crash?&quot; As chaos ensued the people began to ask themselves &quot;Is Java good? Or is Java Evil?&quot; The answer to that question rests in you! I mean this isn't cable news... We don't want to tell you how you're supposed to think!

Wow, what an intro huh? Do you see the subtleness of our opinions about Java? Ha ha ha. Don't let our humor fool you, we like the language. We just love giving it a hard time. I mean if we really hated it would we have spent the time building a course for it?... Maybe...

What is Java exactly? Most developers have used or heard of it. It's been around a while. So, what's the deal with this popular, yet mysterious language?

Depending on whom you ask, you will get a very different opinion about Java. Some developers believe that if you don't use Java then you are not programming correctly, while others think of this language as an abomination. Crazy huh? WiBit.Net will get you to a point where you can make your own opinion about the language!

In our Programming in Java course you will pick up where we left off with the &quot;bold-on&quot; Object Oriented Programming Languages and start your very first Pure OOP language. As with all our courses, you will be treated to an opinion rich introduction in which we discuss the history of the language as well as some great and not-so-great things. Once we get through that it's nothing but learning from there.

By the end of this course you will be able to understand Java and develop your own applications (we hope). What exciting new WiBit.Net adventures lay before you? Just watch and find out!</Description></Course><Course><CurriculumID>1</CurriculumID><CourseID>12</CourseID><Title>Programming in C#</Title><Nickname>C#</Nickname><Description>2001 was quite an amazing year! Besides the release of the first Shrek movie, and the one year anniversary of Y2K (and all its failed doomsayer wannabe prophets), the only other cool thing that happened was the official release of the Microsoft created C# programming language! 6 years before, in the superlative year of 1995, Sun Microsystems stunned the development world with the release of their revolutionary Java language. When Microsoft first took a look at this language, they only had one thing to say: &quot;Ohhhh S**T!&quot; Yes, my friends, the Cyber Giants had been surpassed by a bunch of coffee drinking nerds that were obsessed with Oak trees. Java looked 1,000 years beyond what Microsoft had in its arsenal. They were trying to hang their hat on their highly anticipated yet tragically flawed MFC (Microsoft Foundation Class, aka Microsoft Fried Chicken) framework, but it was clear... Visual Basic was dying... something had to be done (while trying to make it look like VB is still relevant). Microsoft enlisted the help of Anders Hejlsberg to create a new way of developing software! He is known well for his Earth shattering contributions to the world of Bits and Bytes! Yah, he was the guy to shake things up! After thinking about it over, and over again, the final decision was made. Since Microsoft was always known for having the greatest minds in the business, it was inevitable that the decision made by this man and those in his inner circle would be an astounding one... The final decision was. &quot;Ummmm, yah Let's just rip off Java. We'll do the exact same thing, pretend like we aren't, and call it something different. Wouldn't that be COOL.&quot; And this is exactly what they did! That day, C# was born!

Ahh, history is fun, isnt it?

Welcome to Programming in C# from WiBit.Net! You will, once again, be taken under the wing of experienced software developers Kevin and Bryan and given an amazing ride through the ins-and-outs of this glorious language!

What exactly is C#? What does it have to do with this .Net Framework we hear so much about? These questions and so many more will be answered in this amazing course! C# is quite an interesting language because it created clear divisions between programmers in the early 2000's. There was a huge rift between Java and C# back in the day and the aftershocks of these battles are still noticeable today. This has to do with the outright &quot;copying&quot; of Java by Microsoft. Sure, one could make a case that the two languages were very different, and this is true. But, for those of us that remember 2001 clearly, the first time we saw C# we thought, &quot;Hey, wait a minute here! I already know this language.&quot; This closeness (or cloneness) to Java made C# intuitive to learn for many programmers. Programmers that have used C++ and Java were suddenly caught up in a utopian mixture of the two languages and got lost in its spoils. Some programmers got so wrapped up in C# that they refused to use anything else for many many years (until Steve Ballmer firmly took over Microsoft, and we all know whats happened since).

This course is a continuation of our C-Lineage curriculum that takes you from the C to Object Oriented concepts, from OOP concepts to C++, from C++ to Objective-C, from Objective-C to Java, and finally from Java to C#. This gradual step latter of courses are intended to build you into a well-rounded and proficient developer. At the conclusion of this course you will probably know over 80% of what is out there in the job market!</Description></Course></Courses></WiBitNet>